<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac on craig wickesser</title>
    <link>http://craigwickesser.com/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac on craig wickesser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>codecraig@gmail.com (Craig Wickesser)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>codecraig@gmail.com (Craig Wickesser)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 19:37:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://craigwickesser.com/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Mesos using Docker 1.11.1-beta11 on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/05/run-mesos-using-docker-beta11-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 19:37:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>codecraig@gmail.com (Craig Wickesser)</author>
      <guid>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/05/run-mesos-using-docker-beta11-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>Previously I wrote about running Apache Mesos in Docker on Mac OS X using Docker for Mac Beta 8. With the recent update to Docker 1.11.1-beta11 things have changed a bit and so the scripts have to change.
Once again the dockerIp had to be discovered differently and I had to switch docker to use nat networking, instead of the default hostnet.
First, change the networking: pinata set network nat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Mesos using Docker Beta on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/04/run-mesos-using-docker-beta-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 20:30:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>codecraig@gmail.com (Craig Wickesser)</author>
      <guid>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/04/run-mesos-using-docker-beta-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>Previously I wrote about running Apache Mesos in Docker on Mac OS X. Back then Docker worked by using a VM run via VirtualBox. Today, using Docker Beta for Mac, the process is simpler and more like the linux experience.
The scripts I used before only had to be changed to update the way the dockerIp was discovered. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how do find that IP address.
With the Docker Beta there&amp;rsquo;s a command-line tool named pinata which can be used to configure docker:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Email on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/01/secure-email-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 20:06:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>codecraig@gmail.com (Craig Wickesser)</author>
      <guid>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/01/secure-email-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>This will be quick. I use GMail but it lacks the native ability to sign and encrypt email. I did some looking around for desktop email clients for Mac OS X that support S/MIME.
I ended up going with Airmail 2 because it has S/MIME support and it supports Markdown which I like to use.
S/MIME support is provided by a plugin. Follow the instructions after going to the link, you&amp;rsquo;ll ultimately download a zip file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesos on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/01/mesos-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 12:14:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>codecraig@gmail.com (Craig Wickesser)</author>
      <guid>http://craigwickesser.com/2016/01/mesos-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>updated on 04/01/2016 to use mesosphere docker images
Using docker it&amp;rsquo;s simple to get a Mesos cluster running on Mac OS X. I&amp;rsquo;m running Docker 1.9.1 and OS X 10.11.2. We&amp;rsquo;ll be running Zookeeper 3.4.7 and Mesos 0.24.1 (that&amp;rsquo;s the version provided by the docker image I&amp;rsquo;m using for this example).
First we&amp;rsquo;ll start a Zookeeper server, then a Mesos master and a single Mesos slave.
note: I have satellite internet, so my downloads are throttled after I use the data allowance for the month.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>